♪
Eugeo: ELDRIE?
I KNOW THAT NAME.
- Kirito: HEY.
- ( Eugeo gasps )
Kirito: GET READY.
I’M GONNA KEEP HIM BUSY.
WHEN I GIVE THE SIGNAL,
YOU’RE UP.
Eugeo: GOT IT.
Eldrie: USING YOUR CHAINS
AS A WEAPON, EH?
THEN I’LL FOREGO MY SWORD
AND USE THIS INSTEAD.
SYSTEM CALL! ENHANCE ARMAMENT!
- ( Eugeo gasps )
- Kirito: DON’T SWEAT IT.
A WHIP CAN ONLY REACH SO FAR.
Eldrie: HAH!
Kirito: WE’RE SAFE HERE.
( gasps )
OH, SHI--
Eldrie: IMPRESSIVE!
MY DIVINE FROSTSCALE WHIP
IS FAST,
BUT IT SEEMS YOU’RE FASTER.
Eugeo: YOU ALL RIGHT?! ( gasps )
HIS WHIP DID THAT?
Kirito: EUGEO, I’LL TRY
TO FIND A WAY TO STOP HIS WHIP.
YOU SNEAK AROUND BACK.
( Eugeo grunts )
Eldrie: IF YOU’VE
FINISHED PLOTTING,
WE SHOULD WRAP THIS UP.
NOW COME AT ME,
AND KEEP ME ENTERTAINED.
♪
♪ SHINY SWORD, MY DIAMOND ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ IT’S TIME ♪
♪
Kirito: SYSTEM CALL!
GENERATE THERMAL ELEMENT!
Eldrie: GENERATE
CRYOGENIC ELEMENT.
Kirito: FORM ELEMENT,
ARROW SHAPE!
Eldrie: FORM ELEMENT,
BIRD SHAPE.
COUNTER THERMAL OBJECT.
Kirito: DISCHARGE!
Eldrie: DISCHARGE.
( Kirito yells )
( Eldrie chuckles )
- ( Kirito gasps )
- ( Eldrie grunts )
( Kirito groans )
( gags )
( Eldrie sighs )
IT SEEMS I OVERESTIMATED YOU.
HOWEVER, I AM MERCIFUL.
YOU’LL BE UNCONSCIOUS
BEFORE YOU KNOW IT.
♪
( Eugeo yells )
( Kirito yells )
MY TURN!
Eldrie: PERHAPS IT
WAS PRESUMPTUOUS OF ME
TO UNDERESTIMATE YOU EARLIER.
IT SEEMS YOU’VE MANAGED
TO DO ME SOME HARM AFTER ALL.
Kirito: YEAH, WELL,
THAT’S WHAT YOU GET.
Eldrie: I MUST SAY,
YOUR STYLE OF COMBAT,
THERE’S SOMETHING
ODDLY FAMILIAR ABOUT IT.
Kirito: REALLY? THEN I GUESS
YOU MUST HAVE COME UP
AGAINST A SWORDSMAN
OF THE SERLUT STYLE BEFORE.
( Eldrie chuckles )
THAT, MY DEAR CRIMINAL,
IS NOT POSSIBLE.
AS I PREVIOUSLY SAID,
I WAS SUMMONED AS A KNIGHT
TO THIS REALM ONE MONTH AGO.
Kirito: YEAH, RIGHT.
I BET YOU WERE.
( gasps ) HOW’S THAT WORK?
DOES SOMEONE SNAP THEIR FINGERS,
AND YOU COME RUNNING?
( Eldrie grunts )
( gasps )
( Eugeo yells )
Eldrie: RELEASE RECOLLECTION.
( Kirito gasps )
( Eugeo gasping )
( yelling )
Eldrie: NO WONDER
LADY ALICE WAS WARY OF YOU.
YOUR ATTACKS HAVE NO PATTERN,
WHICH IS SURPRISING
AND SLIGHTLY IRRITATING.
WHAT IRRITATES ME MORE
IS YOU FORCED ME TO USE
MY MEMORY RELEASE SKILL.
( Eugeo gasps ) THAT’S IT.
YEAH, NOW I KNOW
WHERE I HEARD YOUR NAME BEFORE.
Eldrie: HMPH.
Eugeo: YOU WERE
THE CHAMPION SWORDSMAN
THIS YEAR
FOR NORLANGARTH EMPIRE,
AND THEN YOU WON
THE UNIFICATION TOURNAMENT.
YOU’RE ELDRIE WOOLSBURG!
Eldrie: CHAMPION?
FROM THE NORLANGARTH EMPIRE?
ELDRIE WOOLSBURG?
Eugeo: IT’S TRUE, SIR KNIGHT.
THIS YEAR,
IF I REMEMBER CORRECTLY,
YOU WON EVERY MATCH
WITH A SINGLE STROKE.
Eldrie: WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?!
THAT’S PREPOSTEROUS! I AM
ELDRIE SYNTHESIS THIRTY-ONE!
I HAVE NEVER HEARD
THE NAME "WOOLSBURG" BEFORE!
Eugeo: BUT--
Eldrie: ENOUGH!
HOLD YOUR TONGUE,
YOU BLASPHEMER!
I-I WAS SUMMONED TO THIS WORLD
BY THE PONTIFEX!
I-I AM HERE
BY ADMINISTRATOR’S WILL!
I-I DESCENDED
AS AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT
FROM THE HEAVENS, I TELL YOU!
( sword clatters )
( groaning )
( both gasp )
( Eldrie screaming )
( gags )
Eldrie: WH-WHAT’S THAT?
♪
Kirito: I BET ALICE
GOT ONE OF THOSE, TOO,
WHEN THEY BLOCKED HER MEMORY
AND CHANGED HER.
( gasps ) ELDRIE!
ELDRIE WOOLSBURG!
( Eldrie groans )
EUGEO, KNOW ANYTHING ELSE
ABOUT HIM?
ANYTHING AT ALL?
SOMETHING TO TRIGGER
MORE OF HIS MEMORY!
( Eugeo grunts ) ELDRIE!
YOUR FATHER
IS ESCHDOR WOOLSBURG,
THE IMPERIAL KNIGHTS’S GENERAL!
YOUR MOTHER’S NAME IS,
I THINK, ALMERA?
- ( Eldrie gasps )
- Eugeo: YEAH, IT’S ALMERA!
Eldrie: A-ALMERA.
MOTHER?
Kirito: THAT’S RIGHT!
REMEMBER HER!
REMEMBER!
( groaning )
Eugeo: KIRITO!
( Kirito yells )
♪
- ( crackle )
- ( gasps )
Eugeo: YOU OKAY?!
Deusolbert: STEP AWAY FROM
KNIGHT THIRTY-ONE, CRIMINALS.
TEMPTING AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT
TO FALL FROM GRACE
IS UNFORGIVEABLE, YOU WRETCHES.
I SHALL PIN YOU DOWN,
THEN RETURN YOU TO YOUR CELL.
( both gasp )
Kirito: THIS WAY!
Kirito: WHICH WAY?
Woman: GO RIGHT!
( Kirito gasps )
EUGEO, GO RIGHT!
♪
Eugeo: DEAD END UP AHEAD!
WHAT DO WE DO?!
- Girl: HEY!
- Kirito: HUH?
Girl: OVER HERE!
Woman: FOLLOW HER!
( Kirito gasps )
( gasps )
( yells )
( moans )
( both gasp )
Kirito: WHERE ARE WE?
( door opens )
Girl: NOW THEY KNOW WE’RE HERE.
WE CAN’T USE
THIS BACKDOOR ANYMORE.
Kirito: THANK YOU.
WE WERE REALLY IN A BIND.
- WHO ARE YOU?
- Eugeo: I’M EUGEO.
IT’S NICE TO MEET YOU.
Kirito: WAIT A SEC.
Eugeo: AND THIS IS KIRITO.
( Kirito groans )
( girl sighs )
( metal clinking )
Eugeo: WE REALLY
APPRECIATE YOUR HELP.
IS THIS, UM, WHERE YOU LIVE?
Girl: NO. OF COURSE IT ISN’T.
COME WITH ME.
( staff rings clinking )
Kirito: SO, UH, ARE WE
IN THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL?
Girl: YES AND NO,
BUT NEITHER OF YOU
HAVE TO WORRY.
ALTHOUGH THIS SPACE
IS TECHNICALLY IN THE CATHEDRAL,
I’VE DELETED
THE REGULAR DOORWAY TO IT.
NO ONE CAN ENTER HERE
FROM THAT POINT NOW.
WELL, UNLESS I INVITE THEM.
( both wince )
♪
( Kirito gasps )
Eugeo: IT’S A LIBRARY.
Girl: INDEED.
THE RECORDS OF THIS WORLD’S
ENTIRE HISTORY ARE HERE,
AS WELL AS THE FORMULAS
OF EVERYTHING CREATED
UNDER THE HEAVENS.
THAT INCLUDES
EVERY SYSTEM COMMAND,
OR WHAT YOU REFER TO
AS "THE SACRED ARTS."
Kirito: W-WAIT.
S-SYSTEM COMMANDS?
WHO ARE YOU?
Girl: MY NAME IS CARDINAL.
I WAS ONCE THE REGULATOR
OF THIS WORLD,
BUT NOW I AM THE SOLE CURATOR
OF THIS GREAT LIBRARY.
Eugeo: ALL OUR HISTORY?
Cardinal: PRECISELY.
THERE IS ALSO
A RECORD OF THE CREATION,
WHEN VECTA AND STACIA
SPLIT THE WORLD
INTO THE HUMAN EMPIRE
AND THE DARK TERRITORY.
YOU MAY READ THEM IF YOU WISH.
BUT, FIRST, WOULD YOU
HOLD OUT YOUR RIGHT HANDS?
Both: HMM?
Cardinal: HMM.
THERE.
- ( Eugeo gasps )
- Kirito: WHOA!
Eugeo: AH-CHOO!
Kirito: UH, YOU FEELIN’ OKAY?
- Eugeo: YEAH.
- Cardinal: HUH.
YOU’RE GOING TO CATCH A COLD
IF YOU STAY
IN THOSE WET CLOTHES.
AT THE END OF THE HALL
THROUGH THERE,
YOU’LL FIND
A SMALL BATH YOU MAY USE.
Eugeo: THANKS A LOT.
I’M GRATEFUL
FOR YOUR HOSPITALITY.
CAN I, UM, SEE THE, UM...
- Cardinal: HMM?
- Eugeo: RECORD OF CREATION?
( Cardinal chuckles )
IT IS LOCATED UP THE STAIRS
IN THE HISTORY SECTION.
AFTER YOU BATHE, YOU MAY
READ IT WITH YOUR SUPPER.
( Eugeo gasps )
YOU’RE MUCH TOO KIND.
I’LL BE BACK IN A BIT, THEN.
( sneezes )
- ( sniffles )
- ( Cardinal sighs )
WHAT THOSE RECORDS
WON’T REVEAL
IS THAT THE PONTIFEX
OF THE AXIOM CHURCH
FABRICATED ALL OF IT.
( Kirito gasps )
LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT.
YOU’RE SAYIN’
THE GODS HERE ARE FAKE?
Cardinal: YES.
THE MYTHS THE PEOPLE
OF THE UNDERWORLD BELIEVE
ARE JUST PROPAGANDA,
ALL INVENTED BY THE CHURCH
TO MAINTAIN ITS CONTROL.
THE GODS’S NAMES ARE REGISTERED
AS SUPERVISOR ACCOUNTS
IN CASE OF EMERGENCY,
BUT THE HUMANS OUTSIDE
NEVER LOGGED IN USING THEM.
( Kirito gasps ) WAIT A SEC.
HOW WOULD YOU KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THE REAL WORLD?
YOU WEREN’T BORN HERE, WERE YOU?
YOU’RE AN OUTSIDER,
JUST LIKE THE SYSTEM ADMINS!
Cardinal: YES, AND I KNOW
YOU’RE AN OUTSIDER, TOO...
KIRITO THE UNREGISTERED.
Kirito: YEAH, I AM.
A COMPANY CALLED RATH
IS THE ONE THAT MADE THIS WORLD.
- YOU KNOW THAT.
- Cardinal: YES, I DO.
Kirito: THEN YOU MUST BE
THE CARDINAL SYSTEM.
YOU’RE AN AUTONOMOUS PROGRAM,
AREN’T YOU? YOU RUN THIS WORLD.
Cardinal:
AH, SO YOU KNOW ABOUT ME.
THEN YOU’VE INTERACTED
WITH MY KIND BEFORE
IN THE OUTERWORLD.
Kirito: OH, YEAH.
BUT YOU’RE DIFFERENT.
AS FAR AS I KNOW,
THE CARDINAL SYSTEM
NEVER HAD A HUMANLIKE INTERFACE,
SO WHAT KIND
OF PROGRAM ARE YOU?
WHAT DO YOU DO HERE?
( Cardinal sighs )
I’LL TRY TO BE
AS SUCCINCT AS POSSIBLE.
BUT, FIRST, EAT.
♪
( Kirito gasps )
Cardinal:
I’VE CAST A SPELL ON IT
THAT WILL HELP
YOUR WOUNDS HEAL FASTER.
Kirito: WOW.
NOW, THAT’S AN ADMIN FOR YOU.
Cardinal: I AM
NOT AN ADMINISTRATOR.
I CAN ONLY MANIPULATE
THE OBJECTS
THAT ARE CONTAINED
IN THIS LIBRARY.
Kirito: OH! CARDINAL,
CAN YOU GET IN TOUCH
WITH SOMEONE
IN THE REAL WORLD FOR ME?
Cardinal: OF COURSE NOT!
IF I COULD DO THAT,
I WOULDN’T BE STUCK HERE
IN THIS DUSTY PLACE
FOR ALL THESE CENTURIES.
UNFORTUNATELY, THE ONLY ONE
WHO HAS THAT AUTHORITY
IS THE PONTIFEX.
( Kirito sighs ) CRAP.
Cardinal: THERE.
I TOLD YOU EARLIER THAT NO GODS
EXIST IN THIS WORLD.
TECHNICALLY, THAT’S TRUE,
BUT THERE WAS ONCE A TIME
WHEN SOMETHING SIMILAR DID.
THAT WAS ABOUT 450 YEARS AGO.
BACK WHEN CENTORIA WAS
NO MORE THAN A TINY VILLAGE,
THERE WERE FOUR GODS.
Kirito: LET ME GUESS.
THEY WERE THE FOUR STAFF MEMBERS
FROM RATH WHO BUILT THIS PLACE.
Cardinal: YOU ARE CORRECT.
TWO MALES AND TWO FEMALES
CAME TO THIS LAND.
EACH COUPLE RAISED EIGHT
CHILDREN EACH ON TWO FARMS.
THEY TAUGHT THEM
TO READ AND WRITE
AND HOW TO RAISE CROPS
AND LIVESTOCK, TOO,
AND THE MORAL ARGUMENTS
OF GOOD AND EVIL,
WHICH FORMED THE BASIS
OF THE TABOO INDEX.
BASED ON HOW EFFECTIVELY
THE FIRST FOUR
WERE ABLE TO PASS DOWN
THESE TEACHINGS,
IT’S CLEAR THAT, AS HUMANS,
THEY WERE
INCREDIBLY INTELLIGENT.
HOWEVER...
THERE WAS ONE AMONG THEM
WHO WAS NOT ONLY BRILLIANT,
BUT DEVIOUS AS WELL.
THE CHILDREN THIS PERSON RAISED
INHERITED SELFISH DESIRES,
SUCH AS THE HUNGER
TO RULE AND CONQUER.
THE OFFSPRING OF THESE CHILDREN
WOULD EVENTUALLY BECOME
THE NOBLES OF THIS LAND,
AS WELL AS THE HIGH MINISTERS
OF THE AXIOM CHURCH.
ONE OF THEM,
THE CURRENT SYSTEM SUPERVISOR,
IS THE PONTIFEX
OF THE AXIOM CHURCH,
A WOMAN WHO CONTROLS
EVERYTHING WITH AN IRON FIST.
SHE CALLS HERSELF ADMINISTRATOR,
THE MOST ARROGANT NAME
IMAGINABLE.
Kirito: THAT NAME...
I HEARD THAT ELDRIE GUY SAY IT.
THAT’S RIGHT.
HE SAID HE WAS, LIKE,
SUMMONED BY THIS PONTIFEX
ADMINISTRATOR OR SOMETHING.
Cardinal: YES. SHE’S THE ONE
I’VE BEEN TALKING ABOUT.
SADLY, THIS ADMINISTRATOR,
WHILE I DON’T LIKE TO ADMIT IT,
IS MY ELDER TWIN SISTER,
SO TO SPEAK.
Kirito: SHE IS? HOW DO YOU MEAN?
Cardinal: I’M GETTING TO THAT.
SEVERAL DECADES
AFTER THE FIRST FOUR LOGGED OUT,
THE FIRST POLITICAL MARRIAGE
WAS ARRANGED
BETWEEN TWO FAMILIES
OF THE LORD CLASS.
FROM THAT UNION,
A BABY GIRL WAS BORN.
( sighs )
HER NAME WAS QUINELLA.
Man: QUINELLA, MY DEAR,
HENCEFORTH, YOUR CALLING
IS TO RESEARCH THE SACRED ARTS.
Quinella: NOTHING WOULD
MAKE ME HAPPIER, FATHER.
THANK YOU.
SYSTEM CALL.
NO ONE ELSE REALIZES IT,
BUT EACH SACRED WORD
HAS ITS OWN MEANING.
"CALL" MEANS TO SUMMON.
"GENERATE" MEANS TO PRODUCE.
( chuckles )
( children laughing )
Girl: COME ON! THIS WAY!
♪
( brush rustles )
( Quinella gasps )
( flying fox chitters )
( Quinella chuckles )
SYSTEM CALL.
GENERATE THERMAL ELEMENT.
FORM ELEMENT, ARROW SHAPE.
FLY STRAIGHT.
DISCHARGE!
( flying fox squeals )
( Quinella giggles )
( laughing )
Woman: LADY QUINELLA, PLEASE,
HELP MY HUSBAND WALK AGAIN!
Quinella: VERY WELL.
SYSTEM CALL.
GENERATE LUMINOUS ELEMENT.
FORM ELEMENT, LIQUID SHAPE.
( woman gasps )
( crowd murmuring )
Husband: IT’S A MIRACLE.
LADY QUINELLA, YOU ARE
THE HOLY CHILD OF STACIA!
Woman 2: BLESS YOU,
LADY QUINELLA!
Cardinal: BUT HER GENTLE SMILE
WAS A MASK.
QUINELLA HAD DEVELOPED
A THIRST FOR POWER,
AND NOW SHE HAD
THE MEANS TO SEIZE IT.
♪
Quinella: VERY SOON,
WE WILL HAVE A PLACE
WHERE WE CAN WORSHIP THE GODS.
( crowd gasping, murmuring )
Quinella: IN ORDER TO CONTROL
THE GROWING POPULATION,
I MUST PUT SOME LAWS INTO PLACE.
TO ENSURE NO ONE ELSE
EXCEEDS MY AUTHORITY LEVEL,
I WILL MAKE HUNTING TABOO.
I WILL OUTLAW MURDER AS WELL.
Man: LADY QUINELLA,
YOU WISHED TO SEE ME?
Quinella: THIS IS A HOLY BOOK
CONTAINING THE COMPLETE WORDS
OF THE GODDESS STACIA.
IT IS CALLED THE TABOO INDEX.
MAKE COPIES, DISTRIBUTE IT
TO EVERY TOWN AND VILLAGE,
AND HAVE THE PEOPLE OBEY IT.
Man: YES, MILADY.
( Quinella gasping )
♪
( panting )
( coughs )
( thunder rumbling )
( chorus vocalizing )
SYSTEM CALL.
OPEN LIST.
READ LIST.
( coughs )
( panting )
( thunder crashes )
SYSTEM CALL.
INSPECT LIST.
( gasps )
Cardinal: FINALLY
QUINELLA OPENED IT...
THE FORBIDDEN DOOR.
( thunder crashes )
IT WAS QUITE THE COINCIDENCE,
ALTHOUGH I SUSPECT SOMEONE FROM
THE OUTSIDE WORLD HELPED HER.
( rings clink )
LET ME SHOW YOU.
SYSTEM CALL!
INSPECT ENTIRE COMMAND LIST!
Kirito: YOU’RE KIDDING.
Cardinal:
WHAT YOU SEE BEFORE YOU,
IS THE FULL CATALOG
OF ALL THE UNDERWORLD’S
SYSTEM COMMANDS.
QUINELLA’S
FIRST ORDER OF BUSINESS
WAS TO RESTORE HER LIFE
AND HALT THE AGING PROCESS.
THEN SHE RESTORED HER BEAUTY.
- IN AN INSTANT...
- ( thunder crashes )
SHE REGAINED THE DAZZLING ALLURE
OF HER LATE TEENS.
( thunder crashes )
( Quinella laughing )
Cardinal: THAT SHOULD HAVE
BEEN ENOUGH TO SATISFY HER...
BUT NO.
FOR QUINELLA, THERE COULD BE
NO ONE EQUAL TO HER.
- ( thunder crashes )
- ( Kirito gasps )
Cardinal:
EVEN THE CARDINAL SYSTEM
WAS SOMETHING
SHE DEEMED A THREAT,
SO SHE DEVISED A WAY
TO SEIZE THE CARDINAL SYSTEM’S
AUTHORITY LEVEL
USING A SACRED ART COMMAND
SHE COMPOSED.
AS A RESULT...
SHE BURNED THE PRIME DIRECTIVE
OF THE CARDINAL SYSTEM
INTO HER FLUCTLIGHT
AS HER OWN BEHAVIORAL PRINCIPLE.
THAT WAY,
IT COULD NOT BE OVERWRITTEN.
SHE JUST WANTED
ITS AUTHORITY LEVEL.
INSTEAD, SHE ENDED UP
FUSING HER SOUL
WITH THE CARDINAL SYSTEM.
"TO UPHOLD ORDER,"
THAT IS THE PRIME DIRECTIVE
OF THE CARDINAL SYSTEM
AND ITS REASON FOR EXISTING.
AS SOMEONE
WHO SPENT TIME IN A WORLD
CONTROLLED BY THE SAME SYSTEM,
YOU SHOULD UNDERSTAND.
CARDINAL OBSERVES THE ACTIONS
OF PLAYERS LIKE YOU,
AND IT CORRECTS ANYTHING
THAT DISRUPTS
THE BALANCE OF THE WORLD
WITHOUT ANY MERCY.
( Kirito gasps )
♪
Cardinal: QUINELLA HAD FAINTED
AND WAS UNCONSCIOUS
FOR AN ENTIRE DAY.
WHEN SHE WOKE UP,
SHE HAD CEASED BEING HUMAN
IN ANY SENSE OF THE WORD.
SHE NO LONGER AGED
OR REQUIRED SUSTENANCE.
HER ONLY DESIRE
WAS TO PRESERVE THIS REALM
IN ITS CURRENT STATE FOREVER.
Quinella: I AM BOTH
RULER AND SUPERVISOR
AND NOW THE PONTIFEX
OF THE AXIOM CHURCH AS WELL.
I AM ADMINISTRATOR.
♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ THE IRIS TO YOU ♪